http://www.adblock.org/en/privacy

Donate
English (US)
Deutsch (DE)
English (US)
Français (FR)
Privacy Policy
Privacy Notice (short version)
Privacy Policy (long version)
Privacy notice (short version)
The following privacy notice shall provide you with a general overview about the collection, processing and use (hereinafter together referred to as "processing") of your personal data. For more information regarding our processing activities, please view our complete Privacy Policy.
What kind of personal data do we process?
While using our products: Adblock Plus or Adblock Browser (automatically, except for Issue Reporter)
Extension updates, subscription downloads, emergency notifications:
Browser version
Extension version
Operating system
Date of last update
IP address
Log file data on Updates page
Additionally, you may manually submit the following information about a webpage using the Issue Reporter:
Browser build, if any
URL
URL of referred webpage, if any, and webpage that opened the given page
Blockable items
Matching filters
Active filter lists
Access to browser settings and installed plug-ins
Enabled extensions (voluntary)
Donations:
Amount of donation
Browser language
Extension name and version
Browser type and version
Operating system and version
Number of notification downloads
Information whether the local storage of the extension configuration is corrupted
Filter subscriptions enabled/disabled
Identifying information about the devices that connect to the payment service provider
For all mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS
Crash reports:
UUID and crash traces in order to help a user associate crash data with specific instances of our products
Instance IDS
Device type
application ID
App and/or extension version
Free space
Free ram
A timestamp of when a crash happened
Event tracking:
App and/or extension version
Demographic data (gender, age)
Device type
Which platforms you are using
Location data based on your IP address (country)
Button clicks and/or navigation patterns
Screens shown
Adblock Browser, based on Chromium, provides Chromium-specific functionality which, however, may send data to Google.
Adblock Browser for iOS (automatically):
Error and crash report data:
Bundle identifier, bundle version and short bundle version string of Adblock Browser
Device type, CPU architecture and version of the operating system
Timestamp of crash
UUID
Plain-text class name and message value of the exception
Instruction pointer, method or function names, signal data, pointer registers and information about the loaded binary images
String / function name identifying the error
For Adblock Plus on desktop, when uninstalling Adblock Plus
Automatically:
Browser language
Extension name and version
Browser type and version
Operating system and version
Number of notification downloads
Information whether the local storage of the extension configuration is corrupted
Filter subscriptions enabled / disabled
Voluntary:
Reason for uninstallation
While using our websites
Automatically:
IP address (stored separately)
The time at which the request was made
The web address accessed
The browser identifier
The referring page
Aggregated analytics data
Voluntary:
Forum registration data
Email address
Data you provide in comments
Feedback and filter data
For user support
User name (contact via social media) and/or email
Device information
Version of Adblock Plus and other applicable tech specifications
URLs the user is having issues with
Adblock Plus issues
Address and transaction ID numbers for donation refunds (voluntary)
In connection with social media
On our social media pages: Usage profiles
Link / button to social media in Adblock Plus: Amount of blocked elements
How do we collect data?
List of techniques and tools we use for data collection.
In our products:
Update checks
Subscription downloads
Sending issue reports
Sending crash reports
In our mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS: via Firebase Analytics
Emergency notification checks
Referring to an uninstall or donation webpage
Data in connection with receiving donations
Log files in connection with Updates page
On our websites:
Cookies
Log files
Data, like name and / or email address and / or communication data, sent by you when using our forum or blog, using the “BECOME A PARTNER” button, or when sharing manually added filters
For non-EU/EEA users only: Via Google Analytics
For user support:
Via email sent by you
From user reviews in App Stores
From forum posts
From Browser Web Store reviews
From social platforms like Facebook and Twitter
Data you provide to us via social media
In connection with social media:
On our social media pages: Cookies
Sharing function in Adblock Plus: Links
How and why do we process your data?
In order to inform you about urgent issues in connection with our products.
To improve and to evaluate our products by processing and analyzing subscription downloads, extension updates, emergency downloads, uninstallation information, and issue reports you send to us.
For technical purposes, such as, but not limited to, preventing security attacks, to improve our website / products, to ensure website / product security.
To analyze aggregated website logs, and for non-EU/EEA users analytics data, to improve our website.
For communication and assistance purposes in our forum and blog.
For discussing and negotiating a partnership with you.
For assisting you with any issues you may have with our products.
For receiving donations that you send to us and for fraud detection.
To promote our products.
In connection with our social media pages, social networks use the data for market research and advertising purposes.
What is the legal basis of data processing?
We process your personal data in compliance with the European General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (“GDPR”), the applicable EU laws and German national data protection laws.
How long do we keep data?
For a period of 30 days:
Issue report data
iOS crash and error reporter data
Website logs
Data related to subscription downloads, extension update checks, emergency notifications
Data related to uninstalling the extension
For a period of 180 days:
In our mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS crash reporting
For a period of 60 days:
event tracking
Blog and forum data as long as the respective comment / account exists
All user support data is deleted one (1) year after closing the respective support case.
For a period of 10 years:
Donation report data
Partner data
Note: “Aggregated usage statistics”, such as analytics data and other data without any connection to a single user, may be retained beyond these periods.
Our values
We collect as little data as possible. As far as anonymous or pseudonymous use is possible we anonymize or pseudonymize your data.
What rights do you have?
Receive information about the personal data processed by us and how we process your data as well as to gain access to such data.
Rectify inaccurate personal data and restrict details.
Receive all your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, as well as having such data transmitted to another controller.
Request erasure of your data, unless such data needs to be retained for legal purposes.
Object to the processing of your data.
Withdraw your consent at any time, when you have provided us with your consent to the processing of your personal data.
Lodge a complaint with the respective supervisory authority.
Questions?
Contact our Data Protection Officer, Dr. Judith Nink, via email or phone.
Privacy Policy (long version)
General information about your privacy
The following information applies to the collection, processing and use of personal data in connection with our services, as but not limited to, the Adblock Plus extension, Adblock Browser and on our websites.
General notes
Who is responsible for data collection and processing (contacts)?
What is personal data?
What is the purpose of data processing and what is the legal basis?
Do we disclose any personal data?
What rights do you have?
Changes to this Privacy Policy
Collection and processing in our products
Collection and processing in our websites
Collection and processing for user support
Collection and processing in connection with social media
Privacy notice for California Residents
General notes
Your protection and data confidentiality is of utmost importance to us ("eyeo", "we", "our"). We take the protection of your personal data very seriously and collect as little data as possible. Nevertheless, collecting data helps our products and websites function correctly, and allows us to communicate with you. Our general privacy policy is to avoid collecting more data than necessary. Collected data is anonymized, if possible, and deleted when no longer needed. This privacy policy shall inform you about the collection, processing and use of your personal data. We gather and use personal data firmly within the provisions of the European General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) (“GDPR”), the applicable EU Laws and German national data protection laws. In the following text we will inform you about the specific data, the scope and the purpose of the collection and use of personal data by eyeo when using our products and visiting our websites.
Who is responsible for data collection and processing (contacts)?
The legal person responsible for the collection, processing and / or use of personal data in connection with our websites and products ("Controller") is:
Controller
eyeo GmbH
Lichtstr. 25
50825 Cologne
Germany
Data Protection Officer
If you have any questions regarding your personal data, please do not hesitate to contact our Data Protection Officer:
Dr. Judith Nink
Phone
+49 (0) 221 / 6430630
Email
email address
Fax
+49 (0) 221 / 64306399
What is personal data?
The purpose of data protection is to protect personal data. Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ("data subject"). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular, by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
This information includes, for example, details such as name and email address, but also nicknames and information in your forum posts.
What is the purpose of data processing and what is the legal basis?
Purpose of data collection and processing
In compliance with Art. 5 (b) GDPR, we collect and process your personal data for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and do not further process your data in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes.
We collect and process your personal data solely for the following purposes:
We collect and process your personal data, such as website logs and data relating to subscription downloads, extension update checks (such data is collected and processed by Google, see Google Privacy Policy), emergency notifications and Issue Reporter data sent by you, for technical purposes. We mainly collect and process such data to prevent security attacks and are thus able to provide our services to you in a secure and data-efficient manner.
We collect and process your personal data relating to subscription downloads, extension updates, emergency downloads, and Issue Reporter data sent to us by you to improve and evaluate our products.
We send emergency notifications in order to inform you about urgent issues in connection with our products.
We collect and process the data you have provided us with in our blog and forum in order to communicate with you and / or to assist you.
We collect data in connection with donations you have made to support us for accounting purposes.
Legal basis of data collection and processing
We collect and process your personal data in compliance with the GDPR and the applicable EU laws and German national data protection laws.
Collection and processing is based on your consent - Art. 6 (1) a GDPR, Art. 4 (11) GDPR
We will always ask for your consent to collect and process your personal data for the aforementioned specific purposes, unless the collection and processing of your personal data is permitted by statutory laws. Where you have provided us with your consent to the collection and processing of your personal data for the aforementioned specific purposes, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time.
Collection and processing is necessary for taking steps prior to enter into a contract - Art. 6 (1) b GDPR
The collection and processing of your personal data may be necessary for the performance of a contract to which you may be a party. Prior to entering into such a contract, the collection and processing of your personal data may also be necessary in order to take steps at your request. This applies for installation (data gathered by the browser and / or app store) and the use of our products.
Collection and processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Controller is subject – Art. 6 (1) c GDPR
Collection and processing of your personal data may be necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject under EU laws or the laws of an EU Member State.
Collection and processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests - Art. 6 (1) f GDPR
The collection and processing of your personal data may be necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests. We collect and process website logs for technical reasons, such as, but not limited to, preventing denial of service attacks. Denial of service is typically accomplished by flooding the targeted machine or resource with superfluous requests in an attempt to overload systems and prevent some or all legitimate requests from being fulfilled. Preventing such overloads of our systems and any security issues by denial of service attacks is in your and our vital interest and therefore we use the website logs. We use information collected and processed via subscription downloads, extension update checks, emergency notifications and feedback data sent by you, for technical reasons, such as, but not limited to, ensuring the security of the extension version used by you. Ensuring the security of our extension is in your and our vital interest and therefore we use such data. Furthermore, we collect and process such data to ensure that our website and extension are constantly improved and adjusted to the changing requirements for an efficient usability and the technical environment. In addition, we collect personal data to remember your privacy settings and/or to keep you logged in. Ensuring the usability of our websites and of our products is in your and our vital interest and therefore we use such data.
Do we disclose any personal data?
We may only transfer your personal data to third parties without informing you separately beforehand in the following exceptional cases as explained below:
If required for legal proceedings / investigations, personal data will be transferred to the criminal investigation authorities and, if appropriate, to injured third parties. We will only do this if there are concrete indications of illegal and / or abusive behavior. We are also legally obliged to give certain public authorities information. These are criminal investigation authorities, public authorities which prosecute administrative offences entailing fines and the German finance authorities.
As part of the further development of our business, it may happen that the structure of eyeo GmbH changes. The legal structure may be adapted, subsidiaries, business units or components may be created, bought or sold. In such transactions user information may be shared with the transmitted part of the company. In the event of a transfer of personal information eyeo GmbH will ensure that it is done in accordance to this privacy policy and the GDPR and applicable EU laws and German data protection laws.
We will not transfer your personal data to third parties as a matter of course without letting you know in advance. We will ask for your prior permission unless the transfer of such data is permitted by GDPR or any other applicable EU laws and German national data protection laws.
International data transfers
For the following services, we use non-EU/EEA service providers. We have carefully selected these external service providers and review them regularly to ensure that your privacy is preserved. The service providers provide sufficient guarantees to ensure an adequate level of data protection and may only use personal data for the purposes stipulated by us and in accordance with our instructions. We also contractually require the service providers to treat your personal data solely in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the European data protection laws:
We use external service provider tools for email (GSuite); for non-EU/EEA users only to analyze your use of our Websites (Google Analytics); for non-EU/EEA users only for A/B testing based on the analytics data (Google Optimize) and for crash reports and event tracking in our mobile products and on Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS (Firebase). These services are provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. In order to ensure an adequate level of data protection, we have entered into a data processing agreement including the EU Standard Contractual Clauses (processors) – Commission Decision C(2010)593. You can access a copy of this agreement here.
We use external service provider tools to receive donations and analyze fraudulent behavior in connection with donations.. This service is provided by Stripe, Inc., 510 Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Some cookies are saved to your browser before proceeding with payment transactions in order to prevent fraudulent use of their services. Stripe collects identifying information about the devices that connect to its services and uses this information for fraud detection. For more information, please consult Stripe’s cookie policy.
We also use external service provider tools for user support. These services are provided by Zendesk, Inc., 1019 Market Street, San Francisco, CA 94103 (Zendesk) and Sprout Social, Inc., 131 S Dearborn Street, 7th floor Chicago, IL 60603 (Sprout).
What rights do you have?
In compliance with the GDPR and the applicable EU laws and German national data protection laws and to the extent legally permitted, you have the following rights to protect your personal data collected and processed by us:
Information, access, rectification and restriction rights
Naturally you have the right to receive, upon request, information about the personal data stored by us about you and information about how we collect, process and store your personal data. Where that is the case, you have the right to gain access to such personal data stored by us. You have the right to request from us the rectification of your inaccurate personal data. Taking into account the purposes of collecting and processing your data, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed. You have the right to request restriction of processing.
Right to data portability
You also have the right (1) to receive all personal data concerning you and which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and (2) to transmit that data to another controller.
Right to erasure of your data
You have the right to demand from us the erasure of your personal data, where – inter alia – one of the following grounds applies:
If we no longer need your personal data for the aforementioned purposes.
If you withdraw your consent on which the collection and processing is based and where there are no other legal grounds for the collection and processing.
If you object to the collection and processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the collection and processing.
Please note, if data needs to be retained for legal purposes pursuant to Art. 17 (3) GDPR, we will restrict the use of the respective data.
Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority
You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the collection and processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.
Right to object to the processing of your data
You have the right to object at any time to the collection and processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, when collection and processing is based on our legitimate interest (Art. 6 (1) f GDPR).
Right to withdraw your consent at any time
You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, when you have provided us with your consent to the collection and processing of your personal data for one or more specific purposes.
How to exercise your rights
To exercise your rights, please contact us via email or mail to:
eyeo GmbH
Lichtstr. 25
50825 Cologne
Germany
Changes to this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time. The respective current version is available at: https://adblockplus.org/privacy.
Collection and processing in our products
Adblock Plus extension
When you use the Adblock Plus browser extension, we collect and process the following data:
Extension update checks
Your browser periodically checks for updates of all your extensions, including Adblock Plus. Some general information - browser version, extension version, operating system, date of last update and your IP address - are transmitted during an update check. After a successful update, a website may be automatically opened. Data stored on this website includes your IP address (solely for the purpose of IT security and only accessible by eyeo's IT Security team), the time at which the request was made, the web address accessed, the browser identifier and the referring page. This data (IP address only aggregated via hashing with a daily changing salt) is used to generate usage statistics as well as to investigate potential security issues and forum or blog spam. Detailed logs are retained for a period of 30 days, after which only the aggregated usage statistics that cannot be connected to a single user remain. Everything else is deleted.
Updates for Adblock Plus for Android and Internet Explorer are handled by the Adblock Plus website and the data transmitted is subject to the Adblock Plus Privacy Policy. Updates to Adblock Plus for Firefox are handled by the Mozilla website and are subject to the Mozilla's Privacy Policy. Updates to Adblock Plus for Chrome are handled by the Google Web Store website and are subject to the Google Privacy Policy. Updates to Adblock Plus for Opera are handled by the Opera Add-ons website and are subject to the Opera Privacy Policy. Updates to Adblock Plus for Safari are handled by the Safari Extensions website and are subject to the Apple Privacy Policy.
Subscription downloads
If you add filter subscriptions to your Adblock Plus installation, the subscription will be requested to regularly retrieve updates. Every update results in the hosting website receiving your IP address as well as some general information like your Adblock Plus version, browser and browser version.
Furthermore, if a subscription download fails on several consecutive occasions, the updated address of the filter list is requested from the AdblockPlus.org domain. The data transmitted includes the Adblock Plus version, subscription address and any information about the error encountered. This data is used to identify issues that have not been reported by subscription maintainers and is subject to this Privacy Policy.
Issue Reporter
Adblock Plus allows you to send issue reports that will be temporarily stored on the AdblockPlus.org website. These reports contain information required to investigate the issue including the Adblock Plus version, browser version, browser build number, if any, URL of referred page, if any, URL of page that opened the given webpage, address of the webpage where the problem is visible, blockable items on the webpage, matching filters, active subscriptions, type of issue report (i.e. false positive or false negative), and a screenshot of the issue (it is possible to remove particularly sensitive sections of the page before the report is sent). Parameter values are removed from all transmitted addresses to avoid unintentionally leaking private information.
You can
voluntarily:
Provide your email address in order for us to request more information from you or to update you on the issue.
Include an optional comment about the issue.
Allow us to access the following browser settings:
Whether cookies are allowed for the given webpage
Whether JavaScript is enabled on the given webpage
Whether private mode is used for the given webpage
Allow us to access a list of your installed plug-ins, including:
File name
Name of plug-in
Allow us to access a list of your enabled extensions, including:
ID
Name
Version
Access to the reports
The processed reports can only be accessed by an individual who knows their unique ID. These IDs are only shared with:
Maintainers of the filter subscriptions mentioned in the report, as EasyList authors, who are not employed at eyeo.
Certain members of eyeo’s filter list team. eyeo will use the reports for troubleshooting and support monitoring purposes only.
Emergency notification
Adblock Plus contains an emergency notification mechanism that allows it to notify users about important issues affecting their Adblock Plus installation. This feature requires all Adblock Plus installations to query an address in the AdblockPlus.org domain regularly to retrieve the list of active notifications. This request makes your IP address visible to the website and also sends some general information like your Adblock Plus version, browser, browser version and the number of previous Adblock Plus downloads (the download number is limited to four, and will be displayed as 4+ after reaching this number). This data allows serving different notifications to different clients and is subject to this Privacy Policy.
Further requests
Adblock Plus may make further requests to AdblockPlus.org as required. For example, a documentation link is clicked or the full list of filter subscriptions needs to be downloaded. These requests are subject to this Privacy Policy.
Uninstallation and donation information
When uninstalling Adblock Plus for desktop and/or donating to us, you will be referred to an uninstallation and/or donation webpage where the following information is automatically collected: Language of your browser, extension name and version, browser type and version, operating system and version, number of notification downloads, information whether the local storage of the extension configuration is corrupted, and whether any filter subscriptions have been enabled or disabled at the time of uninstallation. On a voluntary basis, you can provide us with your reason why you have uninstalled Adblock Plus. We need this information to improve our products.
For donations, we work with payment providers (Stripe, Inc. and PayPalPaypal S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A.). These providers are responsible for processing the data you enter in regards to the
donations you send to us. Processing includes all data you enter into the respective form, as but not limited to, the type of card, cardholder name, credit card details (except full card number), address, country, zip/postal code, and email address. In addition, Stripe collects identifying information about the devices that connect to its services and uses this information for fraud detection. For further information as to how these providers handle the processing of personal data, please refer to Stripe’s Privacy Policy and PayPal’s Privacy Policy. We store the reports the payment service providers present us with for accounting purposes.
Data retention
Data related to subscription downloads, extension update checks, emergency notifications, Issue Reporter data (as well as the full reports and their associated data), and data in connection with uninstallations and donations are automatically removed after 30 days. Only a subset of the data will be kept longer. This includes only the country code of users filing an issue (extracted from the IP address) for analytic purposes, which is stored separately from the full reports and cannot be connected to an individual after deletion of the full reports. Donation report data is stored for a period of 10 years in accordance with the German tax law requirements.
Adblock Plus stores some data in the Firefox profile on your computer. Adblock Plus never transmits this data to any servers, but other extensions and services, such as Firefox Sync, may do so. Most of the data (your preferences, filter subscriptions and custom filters) is unobjectionable privacy-wise. However, filter hit statistics and recent issue reports could be used to reconstruct your browsing history. Adblock Plus treats this information identically to how history data is treated by the browser; this data isn't stored if you are using private browsing mode and is removed if you choose to clear your browsing history.
Adblock Browser for Android
Browser software
Adblock Browser for Android is based on Chromium. Some data collection and processing in connection with Adblock Browser for Android are subject to Google’s Privacy Policy and the additional Google Chrome Privacy Notice. Please note that Adblock Browser automatically connects to Chromium and its service providers to provide security, snippets and other features (Google Chrome Privacy Notice); and when you ask it to, Adblock Browser also connects to Google to provide you with features such as location services (Google Chrome Privacy Notice).
Deviating from the description in Google Chrome's Privacy Notice, Chromium updates are provided under eyeo's control and some features, such as Chrome’s usage statistics and crash reports, are disabled.
All mobile products and for Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS
Crash reporter
In the event of an unexpected crash or error, our mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS collect data relevant for analyzing the cause of the malfunction. The data is used solely for individual troubleshooting (as well as for identifying general defects which lead to unexpected crashes or errors) and is never shared with any third parties other than Firebase from Google, Inc., which we use for analyzing crash reports (crashlytics).
During a crash, the following data is sent:
UUID and crash traces in order to help a user associate crash data with specific instances of our mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS
Instance IDS
Device type
Application ID
App and/or extension version
Free space
Free ram
A timestamp of when a crash happened
Said data is only collected when the application crashes or throws an error. You can opt-out from sending such reports via Settings > Privacy.
Data retention
Crash reporting is retained for 180 days. Firebase retains Instance IDs until the Firebase customer makes an API call to delete the ID. After the call, data is removed from live and backup systems within 180 days.
Event tracking
We also track when you create an event, e.g. when you access the settings. In such a case, this event will be sent to our service provider, Firebase from Google, Inc. Firebase then makes the following data accessible to us:
App and/or extension version
Demographic data (gender, age)
Device type
Which platforms you are using (Android and its respective version)
Location data based on your IP address (country)
Button clicks and/or navigation patterns
Screens shown
This data is solely used to improve our mobile products and Adblock Plus for Safari on macOS and your user experience. You can opt-out from sending such reports via Settings > Privacy.
Data retention
Event tracking with IDs is retained for 60 days. Aggregated reports may be retained for a longer period.
Adblock Browser for iOS
Crash and error reporter
In the event of an unexpected crash or error, Adblock Browser collects data relevant for analyzing the cause of the malfunction and transmits it to eyeo's HockeyApp account. The data is solely used for individual troubleshooting (as well as for identifying general defects which lead to unexpected crashes or errors) and is never shared with any third parties other than HockeyApp.
During a crash, the following data is sent:
Bundle identifier, bundle version and short bundle version string of Adblock Browser.
Device type, CPU architecture and version of the operating system.
Timestamp of when the crash happened.
A generated UUID to prevent duplicate crash reports.
If an exception was thrown, the plain-text class name and message value of the exception.
Low level crash data like instruction pointer, method or function names, signal data, pointer registers and information about the loaded binary images.
During an error, the following data is sent:
Bundle identifier, bundle version and short bundle version string of Adblock Browser.
Device type, CPU architecture and version of the operating system.
Timestamp of when the error happened.
A generated UUID to separate error reports.
A string / function name identifying the error.
Said data is only collected when the application crashes or throws an error. Furthermore, Adblock Browser explicitly asks for permission to send the collected information after the crash or error happened.
In order to learn more about HockeyApps's privacy policy, please consult their Terms of Service as well as their crash report documentation and event report documentation.
Data retention:
All reports stored on our servers are removed after 30 days.
Collection and processing on our websites
When using our websites, as AdblockPlus.org and AdblockBrowser.org (Websites), we automatically collect the following data in order to provide you with our services, and for security reasons:
Automatically collected information
Website logs
All requests to our Websites are recorded in the website logs. Data stored includes your IP address (solely for the purpose of IT security and only accessible by eyeo's IT Security team), the time at which the request was made, the web address accessed, the browser identifier and the referring page. This data (IP address only aggregated via hashing with a daily changing salt) is used to generate usage statistics as well as to investigate potential security issues and forum or blog spam. Detailed logs are retained for a period of 30 days, after which only the aggregated usage statistics that cannot be connected to a single user remain. Everything else is deleted.
Data retention
The request to our Websites, including your IP address, is stored when you create a forum post, submit a contact form, or add a blog comment. This allows administrators to effectively address spam content and security breaches. All stored requests are deleted after 30 days.
Necessary cookies
We use cookies to recognize signed-in users or to store your privacy preferences. Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer with the help of your internet browser. The cookies are necessary to provide you with our services, are not evaluated in any other manner, and are never used to track Website visitors. If you do not want to enable cookies, you can opt against using them by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. Please note that the efficiency and range of eyeo's services may be restricted as a result.
For non-EU/EEA users only: Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service from Google Inc. ("Google"), on our Websites. Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies" (text files stored on your computer that enable us to analyze your use of our Websites). Information generated by the cookies (including your abbreviated IP address) is transmitted to and stored at a Google server in the United States. Google uses this information to assess your use of our Websites, to compile activity reports, and to provide more services connected with the use of our Websites. It is possible that Google may transmit this information to third parties if required by law, or if third parties process this information on behalf of Google.
You can deactivate Google Analytics if you do not want to help us improve our products. But please note that in this case, a cookie will be set that stores your deactivation choice. This cookie is considered a “necessary cookie” and can’t be deactivated.
Change cookie settings
Necessary cookies
Used to remember your privacy preferences. They cannot be switched off.
Tracking cookies
We use these to analyze website traffic.
A/B testing cookies
We use these Google Optimize cookies for A/B testing based on the analytics data.
Save preferences
For non-EU/EEA users only: Google Tag Manager
Our Website uses Google Tag Manager for the implementation of Google Analytics. Google Tag Manager, provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google”), is a solution that allows marketed website tags to be managed using an interface. The Tag Manager tool itself (which implements the tags) is a cookie-less domain and does not register personal data. The tool causes other tags to be activated. These tags then may register data under certain deactivated domains or on a cookie level. This setting will remain in place for all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager.
For non-EU/EEA users only: Google Optimize
Our Website uses the web analysis and optimization service Google Optimize provided by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google”). We use the Google Optimize service to increase the attractiveness, content and functionality of our Website by playing new features and content to a percentage of our users and statistically evaluating the usage change (A/B testing). Google Optimize is a sub-service of Google Analytics.
Google Optimize uses cookies, which enable us to optimize and analyze your use of our Website. The information generated by these cookies about your use of our Website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. We use Google Optimize with activated IP anonymization so that your IP address is shortened by Google within member states of the European Union, or within the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our Website, compiling reports on optimization tests and related website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage.
You can deactivate Google Optimize if you do not want to help us improve our products. But please note that in this case, a cookie will be set that stores your deactivation choice. This cookie is considered a “necessary cookie” and can’t be deactivated.
Change cookie settings
Necessary cookies
Used to remember your privacy preferences. They cannot be switched off.
Tracking cookies
We use these to analyze website traffic.
A/B testing cookies
We use these Google Optimize cookies for A/B testing based on the analytics data.
Save preferences
On adblock.ai
On our website adblock.ai, we automatically collect the following information.
Facebook Messenger integration
We have embedded the Facebook Messenger functionality, owned by Facebook, Inc., into the adblock.ai website to enable you to submit screenshots to our bot (“Adblock AI”) via Messenger, without having to access the Facebook website. Please note that Messenger is hosted by Facebook. We have disabled the function that would otherwise send personal data to Facebook when you access our website; however, when you click on the button to help train Adblock AI with your screenshots (“START NOW”) you will activate Messenger. Only then will some personal data, including IP address, be transferred to Facebook. For more information, please review Facebook's Privacy Policy. If you do not want to transfer data to Facebook, please do not click on the button to send information to Adblock AI through Facebook Messenger.
Information you give to us on a voluntary basis
The Adblock Plus forum and blog are both publicly available to all visitors. If you write a post or comment, we collect and process personal data as follows:
Forum registration
We use personal data you entered during forum registration to form the user's public profile, which is visible to other forum visitors for the purpose that users can associate forum posts with a particular person.
Passwords and email addresses will not be visible to other forum visitors.
Passwords go through one-way encryption before they are stored on the server.
Email addresses are only displayed in the public profile if explicitly agreed to. By default, they are only used for the sending of notifications to which you subscribed.
Note: Registration is not required to read articles in the forum and you can delete your account at any time.
Blog comments
When you add a comment on the Adblock Plus blog, you can optionally specify an email address. Unlike the other fields, the email address is never displayed to other visitors and is only used to notify the comment author about replies to their comments, if any.
Email collection
Campaigns
Some of eyeo's Websites host product campaigns that rely on email collection. For example, you can request a link by email to install Adblock Browser on your mobile device. We do not use third parties to manage these campaigns. Instead, data that you submit is handled in-house (i.e. turned into an email or used to send the email). We will never share or sell your email address, or any other information collected, to any third parties.
Ad blocking partner integrations
If you click on our “BECOME A PARTNER” button, your email client will open with the option to send an email to us. Your email address and all information you send in this email will solely be used to discuss and negotiate a potential partnership with you. Your contact data will be stored in our Customer Relationship Management System. For more more information on how we process our business partner’s data please check: https://eyeo.com/privacy/#privacy_information_business_partner.
Data retention
Data provided by you in connection with our blog and our forum will be retained for the same time as the comment and / or your account exists.
In general, we do not store your email address unless it’s specifically required to execute the related campaign (i.e. email signups for a newsletter or signing up to get notified about a product launch). In cases where we do store your email address, we only store it for the length of time that is needed to execute the campaign (i.e. once you’ve been notified of the launch).
In case you are entering into a partner agreement, please find more information on our retention periods here: https://eyeo.com/privacy/#privacy_information_business_partner.
Collection and processing for user support
For user support, we use a customer relation management software from Zendesk, Inc. (find more information here) that allows for the integration of user support channels, like social media and email responses. In the event that you contact us for support via email and / or our social media channels, we collect the following data in order to help you to solve your issue sufficiently:
User name (contact via social media) and / or email
Device information
Version of Adblock Plus and other applicable tech specifications
URLs the user is having issues with
Adblock Plus issues
Address and transaction ID numbers for donation refunds (voluntary)
All user support data is deleted one (1) year after closing the respective support case.
Collection and processing in connection with social media
Our social media presence
In order to communicate with you, and to inform you about our activities and offers on social networks, we are active on Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, VK, Twitter and LinkedIn. In terms of Facebook, both Facebook and eyeo are jointly responsible for the processing of your personal data (“joint controller”, GDPR Art. 26), even if it is stored exclusively by the respective social network. Therefore, we still inform you about the data processing processes in connection with our presence on the respective social network as follows.
If you follow our respective online presence on one or more of the social networks used by us, please note that your data may be processed outside the European Union / the European Economic Area. However, all the networks we use have agreed to comply with EU data protection standards.
The social networks we use also process your data regularly for market research and advertising purposes. Based on your usage behavior and interests, the networks may create usage profiles which are used, for example, to place advertisements corresponding to your potential interests within and outside of the networks. For these purposes, cookies, which store your usage behavior and interests, as well as possibly also the devices you use, are regularly stored on your computer.
For a detailed overview of the respective processing operations and opt-out options, please visit the website of each social network, listed below. For the assertion of your rights and requests for information, we also refer you to the respective social networks, where you can exercise your rights most effectively. This is because the social networks have access to your data and can therefore directly take appropriate measures and provide you with the respective information:
Facebook
(Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland), Facebook Fan Page based on a joint controller agreement – Privacy Policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/, Opt-Out: https://www.facebook.com and http://www.youronlinechoices.com
Instagram (Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA) – Privacy Policy / Opt-Out: http://instagram.com
Pinterest (Pinterest Europe Ltd., Palmerston House, 2nd Floor, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, Ireland) – Privacy Policy: https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy, / Opt-Out: https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy#section-your-options
VK (VK LLC, 1-N, bld. 12-14, Lit. A, Khersonskaya st., St. Petersburg, Russia, 191024) – Privacy Policy: https://vk.com/privacy/eu
Twitter (Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA) – Privacy Policy: https://twitter.com, Opt-Out: https://twitter.com/personalization
LinkedIn (LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland) – Privacy Policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy, Opt-Out: https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out
Links / buttons to social media
The links / buttons to social networks and platforms (Facebook and Twitter) used within Adblock Plus for the purpose to enable you to share the amount of elements you have blocked with Adblock Plus generally only establish contact between social networks or platforms and you when you click on the links / buttons. This function corresponds to the way a regular online link works. If you click on a corresponding link / button, this opens a new page via the servers of the respective social network or platform. Through this, the operator of the social network is informed that our website has been accessed via your IP address. At the same time, the social network can place cookies on your terminal device or read cookies unless you have prohibited the use of cookies in your browser. For further information on any processing of your personal data by the operators of the social networks or platforms, please refer to the privacy policies of Facebook (https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation) and Twitter (https://twitter.com/privacy).
California Privacy Notice
This section only applies to California residents. It explains how we collect and use Personal Information as well as the rights available to California residents under the California Consumer Protection Act (“CCPA”). The words in this section have the same meaning given to them in the CCPA. Please note that the words as described under the CCPA may be broader than their common meaning.
“Personal Information,” for example, refers to information that identifies, relates to, describes, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to you or your household. Personal Information does not include information that is aggregated or information that cannot be reasonably linked to you.
What Personal Information we collect and how we use it
In order to provide you with our products and services (“Products”), we must process certain Personal Information about you. We do not sell any of your Personal Information, and we never will. For a detailed explanation about the kinds of information that we collect and how we use it, please review the information provided above. Here is a summary of the CCPA categories of Personal Information that we may have collected about you over the past 12 months:
Identifiers;
Internet or other electronic network activity information, including information about your browser, extension, and operating system;
Geolocation data; and
Inferences drawn from any of the information identified that reflect your preferences and attitudes.
We may have collected these categories of Personal Information for the following business purposes:
To personalize the Products we provide to you;
To evaluate and improve our Products;
To provide limited analytic services;
To communicate with you;
To ensure security and functionality of our Products; and
To perform other business purposes.
How we share Personal Information
Subject to the limitations in this Privacy Policy, we share your Personal Information with external vendors (“Service Providers”) that are contractually prohibited from retaining, using, or disclosing Personal Information for any purpose other than the specific business purposes described in the contract. These Service Providers include:
Service providers that analyze your use of our website and test the accompanying data; and
Service providers that support our mobile products; and
Service providers that facilitate user support.
Additionally, we may also share your Personal Information with law enforcement or other third parties as necessary to comply with legal requirements.
Sources from which we collect Personal Information
We receive Personal Information from you, our websites, your device(s), and our external service providers. The categories of sources from which we have collected or received Personal Information include:
You: We collect information that you voluntarily provide, such as registration data on our public forum or information that you send to us as part of issue reports, user support queries, and user reviews.
Your device(s): We receive information from and about the computers, phones, and browsers that you use in connection with our Products.
Our Websites: We collect information about how you interact with and use our websites.
Your Social Media Profiles: We collect information about your social media subscriptions, if you choose to contribute to content in that manner.
Service Providers: We engage vendors to perform business purposes on our behalf and share information with them to provide us with such business purposes including, analytics, mobile product support, hosting of products, and user support.
What are your rights under the CCPA?
The CCPA provides you with the following rights:
Right to Know: you have the right to request that we disclose to you the categories of Personal Information that we have collected, the categories of sources from which we have collected the Personal Information, the business purpose for collecting Personal Information, the categories of third parties with whom we have shared Personal Information, and the specific pieces of Personal Information about you that we have collected;
Right to Request Deletion: you have the right to request that we delete any Personal Information about you that we have collected; and
Right to Non-Discrimination: we will not discriminate against you for exercising any of these rights.
Please note that we have a duty to verify your identity whenever you exercise your Right to Know and/or your Right to Request Deletion. In order to do so, we will request Personal Information from you to match against the Personal Information in our records. In some cases, we may also request additional documentation to verify your identity.
Please also note that the CCPA allows you to exercise these rights yourself or to designate an authorized agent who will exercise these rights on your behalf. In the event that an authorized agent exercises rights on your behalf, we may request a written permission from you that establishes the individual as your authorized agent as well as other information necessary to verify the identity of the authorized agent.
To exercise any of these rights, please submit a request to email address.
Contact for more information
If you have any questions about this section or how to exercise your rights under the CCPA, please contact us.
October 2020
Cookie notice
We use some cookies to give you the best experience on our website. By using our site you are aware that we are using cookies and you can change this any time. Learn more
Ok, got it
Settings
Settings icon
Necessary cookies
Used to remember your privacy preferences. They cannot be switched off.
Tracking cookies
We use these to analyze website traffic.
A/B testing cookies
We use these Google Optimize cookies for A/B testing based on the analytics data.
Save preferences
Cookie preferences
Close icon
We use some cookies to give you the best experience on our website.
Read more
Ok, got it
Change settings
We use some cookies to give you the best experience on our website. By using our site you are aware that we are using cookies and you can change this any time. Learn more
Necessary cookies
Used to remember your privacy preferences. They cannot be switched off.
Tracking cookies
We use these to analyze website traffic.
A/B testing cookies
We use these Google Optimize cookies for A/B testing based on the analytics data.
Save preferences
